

About Me

Hi, I'm Fan Suen and an experienced designer working in Shanghai, I've been learning and engaging in design for years, my passion is making products with great User Experience. I have tackled difficult design challenges, mentored teams and shipped products with great UX.

I achieve results by recognizing the underlying patterns in a design that can make or break a design. I understand what can be dropped, what needs to be retained, and what needs to be developed. Finally, I know how to package design requirements for developers to make great products.

Platforms I've been working on include desktop, web, tablet and mobile. Experienced in storytelling and create user scenario, storyboard and low-fi motion graphic video to communicate with users and stakeholders.

Know more by visiting my website: http://fansuen.me/

Experience

Senior Design Manager @ IngageApp (2018.04 - Present)

Design and user experience leader, adept at managing UX teams and define design guidelines, delivering great solutions to complex design problems. Astute at identifying underlying patterns that simplify a design and make implementation easier. Solid at collaborating with PM and engineers to ensure implementation.

Senior UX Designer @ Alibaba Group (2017.07 - 2018.04)

Product owner and designer of a rapid interface builder called Aimake, by which anyone can build interfaces using Ant Design components with drag&drop, and the front-end engineers are freed from colors and pixels.

In charge of design International Risk Management softwares and Safety Compliance system over cross-border electronic business platform.

UX/UI Designer @ SAP SME (2014.10 - 2017.07)

Responsible for designing SaaS products for small & medium enterprise, building design guidelines for SAP Anywhere. Responsible for building Finance SaaS Guideline, UX patterns and UIKit.

In charge of design Anywhere Inbox, participate in design Anywhere Show and Sell, SAP XLR and Anywhere E-Shop.

UX/UI Design Intern @ SAP CI&SP (2014.03 - 2014.09)

Responsible for design a global container logistics information system named TRP(Transportation Resource Planning) running on SAP HANA. Apply "Design Thinking" to design process. Learning deep into SAP Fiori Design Guideline and adopt it in solving complex product requirements.

Design History Researcher @ Nobel (2012.12 - 2013.12)

Major subjects: "Infinite Ask - Kan Tai-Keung Solo Exhibition", "Shanghai support national Industry Construction from the 1950s", "Recent Chinese Industrial Design History".

Content arrangement for "Chinese Industrial Design Museum". Writing chapters for "Chinese Industrial Design Archives".

Education

Industrial Design - Marster @ ECUST (2012.09 - 2014.11)

Major in Product Design and Design History, main courses are design theory, design construction, design management, Interaction design, design psychology, design history. Design and build websites and mobile apps for start-up companies.

Industrial Engineering - Bachelor @ Jiangsu University (2008.09 - 2012.07)

Major in Industrial Design engineering, main courses are ergonomics, design science, aesthetics, mechanical engineering, sketch, 3d modeling, vehicle design. Paticipate in website construction and promotion in local firm.

Contact Me

+86 188 1823 7108 fansuen@outlook.com

User Experience Design

Skills

User Experience Design	
User Interface Design	
Interaction Design	
Usability Testing	
Web App Design	
Mobile App Design	
User-Centered Design	
Rapid Prototyping	
Information Visualization	
HTML+CSS	

Abilities

Team Management	
Project Management	
Team Leadership	
Public Speaking	
Design Strategy	
Agile Methodologies	

Languages

Mandarin	
English (CET-6)	

Hobbies

```
design product travel

social science history art

android iOS car

technology
```





